<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on RobinCamarasa</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in About on RobinCamarasa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 17:25:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://robincamarasa.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Erasmus MC - Ph.D. student</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/education/erasmus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/education/erasmus/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lycée Fermat - Classes Préparatoires</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/education/prepa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/education/prepa/</guid><description>Mathematics Algebra: Set Theory Algebraic Calculations and Trigonometry Complex Numbers Real Numbers and Numerical Sequences Arithmetic Usual Algebraic Structures Polynomials and Rational Fractions Vector Spaces and Linear Applications Endomorphisms Symmetric Group Calculus: Differential and Integral Calculus Functions of a Real Variable with Real or Complex Values Limits and Continuity Differentiability Convexity Asymptotic Analysis Integration Differential Calculus and Optimization Probability: Probabilities on a Finite Universe, Random Variables, and Laws Expectation and Variance Discrete Random Variables Analysis: Topology of Normed Vector Spaces Numeric and Vectorial Series Sequences and Series of Functions, Power Series Real Pre-Hilbert Spaces Discrete Summation Procedures Functions of Two Variables Integration over an Arbitrary Interval Ordinary Differential Equations Vector Functions Physics &amp;amp; Chemistry Waves and Signals Kirchhoff&amp;rsquo;s circuit laws Oscillators Linear Filtering Induction and Laplace Forces Periodic Signals Digital Electronics Kinetics and Mechanics Description and Parameterization of Point Motion Newton&amp;rsquo;s Laws Energetic Approach to Point Motion Angular Momentum Motion in a Conservative Central Force Field Motion of a Solid Non-inertial Reference Frame Laws of Solid Friction Optics Scalar Model of Light Waves Superposition of Light Waves Interferential Device using Wavefront Division: Young&amp;rsquo;s Double-Slit Experiment Interferential Device using Amplitude Division: Michelson Interferometer illuminated by a Spatially Extended Source Electromagnetism Motion of Charged Particles in Electric and Magnetostatic Fields Electrostatics Magnetostatics Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s Equations Electromagnetic Field Energy Propagation and Radiation Thermodynamics Principles of Thermodynamics Thermodynamic Machines Heat Transfers Quantum Physics Wave Function and Schrödinger Equation Stationary States of a Particle in Piecewise Constant Potentials Non-Stationary States of a Particle in an Infinite Potential Well Elements of Statistical Thermodynamics Boltzmann Factor System with Discrete Energy Spectra Classical Heat Capacities of Gases and Solids Chemistry Chemical Transformations in Aqueous Solution Relationships between the Structure of Chemical Entities and Macroscopic Physical Properties Structure and Physical Properties of Solids First Principle of Thermodynamics Applied to Physicochemical Transformations Second Principle of Thermodynamics Applied to Physicochemical Transformations Thermodynamic Study of Redox Reactions Kinetic Study of Redox Reactions: Current-Potential Curve Storage and Conversion of Chemical Energy in Electrochemical Devices Corrosion Computer science Computer science structures Number Representation Data Structures Immutable Recursive Types and Trees Applications of Trees Basics of Graphs and Shortest Paths Advanced Graphs Languages and Automata Paradigms Recursive Programming Introduction to Functional Programming Dynamic Programming Logic Syntax and Semantics of Propositional Logic Natural Deduction for Propositional Logic Other Databases Complexity analysis</description></item><item><title>Mines de Saint-Etienne - Master of science (ICM Engineering degree)</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/education/emse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/education/emse/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Git worktree for AI research</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/git-worktree/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 17:25:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/git-worktree/</guid><description>Today, a short blog post to share my excitement about a git feature that I recently discovered : git-worktree. I&amp;rsquo;d like to tank the @Primagen for sharing it!
NB: This article suppose that your are familiar with git and will not explain terms such as checkout, push, pull&amp;hellip; Also this is not a tutorial on how to use git-worktree.
What is git-worktree? I like to think of git-worktree as synchronised local git repositories.</description></item><item><title>Generating ASCII-art</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/ascii-art/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 12:25:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/ascii-art/</guid><description>This post is mostly an excuse for me to &amp;ldquo;document&amp;rdquo; the code that generates the thumbnails of this website, (and also to remember how I did it). Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into it.
Requirements I want a simple program that transforms a image into it&amp;rsquo;s ASCII art equivalent:
The program should be short The program should be easy to modify The program should accept the different popular imaging formats (PNG, JPG, JPEG&amp;hellip;) The program should produce light images (below 200kB) I should be able interact with the program through a command line interface (CLI) Now, I know what I need let&amp;rsquo;s go for it :)</description></item><item><title>DIY - indoor aromatic garden</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/diy-aromatic-plants-pot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 08:25:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/diy-aromatic-plants-pot/</guid><description>Today, I write a short post about how to build an inside aromatic garden from scratch. So put-on your indoor gardening boots (whatever that means), and follow the guide.
Why doing an aromatic garden? I am french, and obviously &amp;mdash;as clichés are always based on something&amp;mdash; I like to cook. A big problem though is that the aromatic herbs of my local super-market horrible: the thyme is barely dried, the basil molds in a couple days&amp;hellip; It frustrates me that my cooking suffers from such stupid considerations.</description></item><item><title>A Free Password Manager</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/pass-a-free-password-manager/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 08:22:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/pass-a-free-password-manager/</guid><description>For all those years, my friends and colleagues used to make fun of people&amp;rsquo;s digital security: &amp;ldquo;People are stupid. They use 12345678 as their main password.&amp;rdquo; I was smiling and nodding, but deep down, I knew that having a pawned mail address and the same weak password on dozens of websites would not make me a poster boy for personal data security. I felt guilty about it, but I never really had the motivation to dive into it.</description></item><item><title>Differentiable Boundary Point Extraction for Weakly Supervised Star-shaped Object Segmentation</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/scientific_publications/midl_2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 08:22:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/scientific_publications/midl_2022/</guid><description>Talk Your browser does not support the video tag.</description></item><item><title>A Quantitative Comparison of Epistemic Uncertainty Maps Applied to Multi-Class Segmentation</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/scientific_publications/melba_2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/scientific_publications/melba_2021/</guid><description>Talk</description></item><item><title>TU Delft Clinical technology master Python course - Teacher</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/python_course/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/python_course/</guid><description>You can find below an example of assignment I wrote for the course.
Assignment</description></item><item><title>Quantitative Comparison of Monte-Carlo Dropout Uncertainty Measures for Multi-class Segmentation</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/scientific_publications/unsure_2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/scientific_publications/unsure_2020/</guid><description>Talk</description></item><item><title>Erasmus MC - Scientific programmer</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/sp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/sp/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Erasmus MC - GPU cluster administration</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/gpu_cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/gpu_cluster/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bayesian Deep Learning</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/reasearch_project/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/reasearch_project/</guid><description>In this 3 month research project, I wrote a short literature review and a report in the form of an article to summarize my findings about Bayesian Deep Learning.
Report</description></item><item><title>DataGenius - Internship</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/data_genius/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/data_genius/</guid><description>The report of my 6 month internship. Due to the requirement of my school it is entirely written in French.
Report</description></item><item><title>Erasmus MC - Internship</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/emc_internship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/positions/emc_internship/</guid><description>A short report (due to my school requirements), about the topic of my internship: Applying Gated Recurrent Units to medical imaging segmentation.
Report</description></item><item><title>Phillips Hue Manager</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/phillips_hue_manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/phillips_hue_manager/</guid><description>At that time, my English was a bit shacky sorry about that. However, I leave the report online if somebody want to dig into it (and also a bit out of nostalgia).
Report</description></item><item><title>Nutritive coach</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/nutritive_coach/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/nutritive_coach/</guid><description>At that time, my English was a bit shacky sorry about that. However, I leave the report online if somebody want to dig into it (and also a bit out of nostalgia).
Report</description></item><item><title>Apple reconstruction</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/interdisciplinary_project/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/interdisciplinary_project/</guid><description>At that time, my English was a bit shacky sorry about that. However, I leave the report online if somebody want to dig into it (and also a bit out of nostalgia).
Report</description></item><item><title>How to Shuffle a Deck</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/how_to_shuffle_a_deck/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/experience/projects/how_to_shuffle_a_deck/</guid><description>At that time, my English was a bit shacky sorry about that. However, I leave the report online if somebody want to dig into it (and also a bit out of nostalgia).
Report</description></item></channel></rss>