<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cli on RobinCamarasa</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/tags/cli/</link><description>Recent content in cli on RobinCamarasa</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 17:25:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://robincamarasa.github.io/tags/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Git worktree for AI research</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/git-worktree/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 17:25:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/git-worktree/</guid><description>Today, a short blog post to share my excitement about a git feature that I recently discovered : git-worktree. I&amp;rsquo;d like to tank the @Primagen for sharing it!
NB: This article suppose that your are familiar with git and will not explain terms such as checkout, push, pull&amp;hellip; Also this is not a tutorial on how to use git-worktree.
What is git-worktree? I like to think of git-worktree as synchronised local git repositories.</description></item><item><title>Generating ASCII-art</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/ascii-art/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 12:25:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/ascii-art/</guid><description>This post is mostly an excuse for me to &amp;ldquo;document&amp;rdquo; the code that generates the thumbnails of this website, (and also to remember how I did it). Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into it.
Requirements I want a simple program that transforms a image into it&amp;rsquo;s ASCII art equivalent:
The program should be short The program should be easy to modify The program should accept the different popular imaging formats (PNG, JPG, JPEG&amp;hellip;) The program should produce light images (below 200kB) I should be able interact with the program through a command line interface (CLI) Now, I know what I need let&amp;rsquo;s go for it :)</description></item><item><title>A Free Password Manager</title><link>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/pass-a-free-password-manager/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 08:22:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://robincamarasa.github.io/posts/pass-a-free-password-manager/</guid><description>For many years, my friends and colleagues used to make fun of people&amp;rsquo;s digital security: &amp;ldquo;People are stupid. They use 12345678 as their main password.&amp;rdquo; I was smiling and nodding, but deep down, I knew that having a pawned mail address and the same weak password on dozens of websites would not make me a poster boy for personal data security. I felt guilty about it, but I never really had the motivation to dive into it.</description></item></channel></rss>